Kosaka!
香坂！
Kagiya?
鍵谷？
What happened?
怎麼了？
I'm sorry.
對不起
I'll go home.
我還是回去好了
Wait, please.
請等一下
I'm sorry about the other day.
之前的事情，我很抱歉
Huh?
什麼？
For coming on so strong.
強迫你做那些事
It must have grossed you out.
你一定覺得很不舒服吧？
I'm sorry.
對不起
Wait, Kagiya!
等一下，鍵谷
No,
不
not at all.
完全不會
Huh?
咦？
That was…
那是…
my problem.
我的問題
"My problem"?
“我的問題”？
You're soaking wet.
你都溼透了
Maybe it's better if we go somewhere else.
要不要換個地方比較好？
Okay.
好
If you don't mind,
你不介意的話
we can go to my place.
也可以來我家一下
That was my problem.
那是…我的問題
What kind of problem does he have?
鍵谷的問題是什麼呢？
Is he asexual?
是無性戀嗎？
He doesn't like women that way?
還是沒辦法和女生做那種事？
Or am I the problem?
還是因為我？
For now, he ran through the pouring rain to follow me,
總而言之 他都淋得溼透了也要追過來
so I should hear him out.
就好好地向他問清楚吧
Thank you.
謝謝你
For the clothes too.
連衣服都借給我了
Don't worry about it.
沒什麼
They're a bit small, aren't they? I'm sorry.
果然還是有點小吧？不好意思
It's fine.
不會
Right.
對了
I'm making tea, so please take a seat.
我剛剛泡了茶，你請坐吧
Okay.
好
You don't have to tell me if you don't want to.
如果不想說的話 可以不用勉強告訴我
Honestly, I…
老實說…
thought you hated me now.
我以為已經被你討厭了
So just the fact that you're here…
所以你像這樣特地跑過來…
I'll tell you.
我會說的
Huh?
咦？
I'll tell you everything.
我會向你好好說明一切的
Okay.
好
Sho…
將…
Shogi.
將棋
Shogi?
將棋？
Have you ever tried playing it?
你有下過將棋嗎？
I tried that one game. Where you pile the tiles up and slide them.
我有玩過疊將棋 就是把棋子疊起來然後弄倒的那種
I've…
我…
Played shogi since I was seven years old.
七歲的時候開始下將棋
Since you were seven?
七歲開始？
Yes.
對
It started out as something I did to pass time.
一開始，只是為了打發時間
When I was playing,
但在下棋的時候
I'd be so focused, I'd forget about everything else.
我能夠很專注，並且忘掉許多事情
Check.
將軍
I give up.
我認輸了
That's a good move.
真是出色的一步
Well played.
下得很好
It was fun.
很開心
So…
所以…
I joined a training facility, and aimed at becoming a pro player.
我加入了養成機構 認真地想朝職業邁進
You mean professionally?
職業棋士嗎？
Yes.
對
I couldn't imagine myself doing anything else.
我不能想像自己 從事將棋之外的工作謀生
But…
但是…
If I couldn't go pro before I turned 26, I would have to quit.
如果我在26歲後 沒能成為職業選手，就必須退出
Those are the rules.
這是規定
I resign.
我輸了
And…
我…
I was unable to do so.
沒能當上職業棋士
Even if you dreams don't come true,
就算沒實現夢想
you still have to live on.
還是得繼續生活下去
All I had ever done was play shogi, so I had no idea what to do with myself.
因為一直都在練將棋 也不曉得接著要怎麼生存下去
I just…
所以我…
searched for a job requiring only a high school diploma and no experience.
找了一個只要高中畢業 沒有工作經驗也可以的工作
I moved out,
搬離家裡
and told myself to go on with life without thinking about shogi.
過著不再去想將棋的生活
But…
但是…
When I was here last time…
之前來這裡的時候…
Another remarkable achievement.
又一次取得出色成就
Shogi player Shinta Fujimoto
將棋選手藤本新太
got a historic 29th consecutive victory by defeating Motojima Akio
在王將戰首戰擊敗本島昭夫
in the opening match of the Osho Title Tournament League.
取得歷史性的29連勝
Shinta Fujimoto back in January of this year…
藤本新太在今年一月回歸…
Kagiya?
鍵谷？
I'm sorry.
對不起
It had already been three years,
明明都已經過了三年了
I didn't know it would still hurt this badly.
我沒想到這件事的傷害這麼大
I haven't moved forward at all since.
我從那之後一點進步也沒有
When I realized, I was disgusted with myself.
想到這裡，我就開始厭惡自己
So, when you called me…
所以，當你打給我的時候…
I just couldn't pick up.
我沒辦法接電話
I am really sorry.
真的非常對不起
Don't be.
不會啦
You did nothing wrong.
完全不是你的關係
It's me.
是我
I was just running away.
一直在逃避而已
Huh?
咦？
I'm sorry.
抱歉
Why?
為什麼？
Because
因為…
you seem so sad.
你看起來很難過
Crying…
就算哭泣…
doesn't change anything.
也一點意義都沒有
Painful things,
痛苦的事情
are best just tucked away.
全部藏起來就好了
-Thank you for speaking to us. -My pleasure.
-請多指教
First of all, congratulations on winning the Tsume Shogi Championship.
首先，恭喜你在之前的 詰將棋冠軍賽中取得優勝
Thank you.
謝謝
What is your next goal?
今後你有什麼目標呢？
-I want to go pro… -Yes?
-將來我想成為職業選手… -是
I hope to eventually reach the Eight-Dan rank.
最終希望能達到八段
That's exciting.
真是令人期待
But don't you think you'll become the youngest player in history to go pro?
但你沒想過在那之前 你會成為史上最年輕的職業棋士嗎？
I will do my best. Thank you.
我會盡力表現，謝謝
I thought I would be fine if I just ignored the game.
我以為只要不去看就沒事
But I…
但…
I…
我…
was so sad.
很難過
I was sad.
我很悲傷
I wanted to cry.
我很想哭
-Do you want a sip? -Yeah. I'll try.
-要喝嗎？ -要，我要喝
What's your type?
你喜歡的類型是什麼？
Someone who's fun to be with.
在一起時會很開心的人
I want someone who makes me smile.
能夠自然而然讓我微笑的人
It is fun some of the time, but…
雖然我也有覺得開心的時候…
Hmm? What?
嗯？什麼？
Oh! D.Pool!
喔，是D.Pool！
-It's such an emotional album. -The second track is amazing, right?
-那張專輯很動人吧？ -第二首超棒的，對吧？
The one that starts with the piano? That one is so good.
開頭是鋼琴的那首？ 我懂，那首超棒的
Even if it's fun, if he's not handsome…
雖然很有趣，但不是帥哥果然不行
IT'S A MATCH!
（配對成功）
HELLO I'M FREE TONIGHT DO YOU WANT TO GRAB A DRINK?
（晚安，我今晚有空 要不要一起喝杯茶？）
Touya?
東也？
I never expected him to swipe back.
我沒想到他會滑回來
Why is someone so handsome interested in me?
這樣的帥哥為什麼會對我有興趣？
Is it an MLM?
該不會是直銷吧？
His bio looks normal though.
但個人資料看起來很普通
Guess it won't hurt to meet up.
總之先見個面看看吧
TOUYA 26, TOKYO
（東也，26歲，東京）
Ren?
小蓮？
Hi. I'm Touya.
你好，我是東也
H-Hello. I'm Ren.
你好，我是蓮
Huh.
這樣啊
This is a cute café.
真是可愛的咖啡廳呢
What did you order?
你點了什麼？
L-Lemonade.
檸…檸檬水
That's nice.
真不錯
What should I get?
我要喝什麼好呢？
Excuse me.
不好意思
No hotel right away.
沒有要馬上去旅館
Look, isn't he handsome?
你看，那個人是不是很帥？
He's so good-looking.
真的很帥耶
Of course everyone's looking.
果然大家都會注目呢
They're probably wondering why he's with someone as ugly as me.
別人會覺得 為何要和我這種醜女在一起吧？
Are you okay?
怎麼了？
Ah, I'm fine.
啊，沒事
W-What?
怎…怎麼了？
I was just thinking, you're stylish.
我只是覺得你很時髦呢
Huh? Not at all.
什麼？才沒有啦
Your earrings are pretty.
耳環很可愛啊
I don't think so.
我不覺得可愛就是了
Really?
是喔？
I think they are.
我是覺得可愛啦
What's his deal?
這個人是怎麼回事？
I probably have to make tea again.
我可能要重泡一壺茶了
I don't want to let go yet either.
我也還不想放開
I'm sorry.
對不起
It's fine.
沒關係
I thought I had to give up on this.
我還以為不能再碰你了
-It feels good. -Huh?
-好舒服 -嗯？
Ah… I'm sorry.
啊…對不起
I said that out loud.
我發出聲音了
Me too.
我也是
Huh?
什麼？
I feel good too.
我覺得很舒服
Thank you for treating me.
謝謝招待
Thank you for keeping me company.
謝謝你今天陪我
I have somewhere I need to go now…
我等一下還有事…
Okay.
好，我知道了
I'm not good enough after all.
果然我還是不夠好吧？
Ren.
小蓮
Can I text you?
我還可以聯絡你嗎？
Huh?
什麼？
Give me your details.
告訴我你的聯絡方式吧
Yeah. Uh…
嗯，等一下…
This is my ID.
這是我的ID
Thanks.
謝謝
He wants to see me again.
他還想再和我見面
Got it. Thanks.
有了，謝謝
Sure.
不會
See you.
下次見囉
Kissing…
接吻…
feels this nice…
是這麼舒服的事情啊
I want to
我想和鍵谷…
do more with him.
再多做一點
I've never thought about anyone this much.
這是第一次 我竟然會這麼想念一個人
I want to call him.
好想打給他
Can I?
可以嗎？
Do you want to go to a museum this weekend?
這個週末，你想一起去美術館嗎？
Kagiya's scent is so calming.
鍵谷的味道，好讓人安心
Kosaka.
香坂
Don't you think someone else would be better?
如果不是我會更好嗎？